prbot.com 2011-11-02

# Free Press Release Distribution | Online Press Release Service - PRbot.com

Your privacy is extremely important to us. We strive to ensure that your online experience with will be safe and satisfying in ever way.

As we collect various kinds of information about our site's users, we think you should completely comprehend our privacy policy and its terms and conditions, including those concerning the use of that information. The privacy policy outlined below describes what information we gather and the manner in which we use it.

## Information We Track and Gather:

We gather two types of information:

  * Information users provide by optional, voluntary submissions, including contacting an author, to receive our electronic newsletters, to email a friend, or any other similar reasons.
  * Information we gather by aggregated tracking information derived mainly from counting page views on our website. This lets us improve our content according to our readers' needs. We never divulge any information about any individual user to a third party.

We Gather User Information in the Following Manner:

### Optional Voluntary Information

We offer the following free services, all of which require some kind of voluntary submission of personal information by our users:

#### 1.      Electronic Newsletter

We offer an optional [free electronic newsletter](http://www.prbot.com/newsletter_account.html) to our users. We collect the email address and other information of users who subscribe. Said information is used to send our subscribers customized electronic newsletters and is not shared with any third parties. Users may unsubscribe from this mailing list by following a link in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page.

#### 2.      Press Release Submission

We offer an optional [free press release submission](http://www.prbot.com/submit-free-press-release.html)  to our users. Any information (except "Admin Email" if different from "Contact Email") that is gathered may automatically be published on our site and made available to site visitors, search engines, other sites through RSS feeds, electronic newsletter subscribers, and by any other means. We may send a one-time confirmation email to the provided email address.

#### 3.      Press Release Account

We offer an optional [free press release account](http://www.prbot.com/account.html) for users who are interested in advanced  features. Any information gathered will be used to customize the user's experience and is not shared with third parties. We may send a one-time confirmation email to the email address provided.

#### 4.      "E-mail this to a friend"

Our site users can choose to forward electronically a link, page, or document to a third party by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide her email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used to inform the recipient regarding who sent the email. For security purposes, the user's IP address is also sent to the recipient. Most of the online as well as offline email programs do the same. The user's information is not used for any other purpose.

#### 5.      "Contact Author"

Our users can choose to contact a press release author electronically by clicking "Contact Author". The user must provide her email address. This information is used to inform the recipient of who sent the email. For security purposes, the user's IP address is also sent to the recipient. Most of the online as well as offline email programs do the same. The user's information is not used for any other purpose.

#### 6.      Polling

We sometimes may offer interactive polls so that users can share their opinions with other users more easily and find out what our audience thinks about important issues. We may use a system so that users can vote once on a particular question. Opinions or any other poll information are aggregated and are unidentifiable to any particular user.

#### 7.      Surveys

We may occasionally conduct user surveys to target our content to our audience more effectively and to improve services. Any information gathered will not be shared with third parties.

#### 8.      Preferences

Users may voluntarily provide personal preferences, such as time zone. Any information so gathered will be used to customize the user's experience and will not be shared with third parties.

### Children

We never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requring parental consent.

### Usage Tracking

We track user traffic patterns throughout our sites; however, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. We do categorize overall usage statistics according to user's domain name, browser type, refering page, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). We compile the number of unique visitors for each press release to display the most popular press releases on top.

We sometimes track and catalog the search terms that users enter in our search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users prefer based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but how well each page performs. This assists in continuing to build a better service.

### Cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain personal Information, although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. The only personal data a cookie contains is information you supply. A cookie cannot read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other websites. We use cookies to track user traffic patterns, as described above.

## Use and/or Sharing of Information

We may use any information voluntarily provided by our users to enhance their experience using our network of sites, whether providing interactive or personalized elements on the sites, or to prepare better future content based on our users' interests.

As stated above, we use information voluntarily provide by our users to send out electronic newsletters and to allow our users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums.

We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users prefer, based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but how well each page performs. This assists us in continuing to build a better service. We track search terms entered in our search function as one of many means of determining what interests our users. We do not track which terms a particular user enters.

We compile aggregated reports regarding our user demographic and traffic patterns for our advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and lets our users receive advertisements that are more pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked its ad. We will not disclose any information about individual users except to comply with applicable laws or valid legal processes, or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

We may share limited aggregate reports with our users so that they may learn how their content is performing.

We permit third party advertisements on our site to support our site's function. Some advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information, including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. Generally, this is used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). You can view their privacy policy by [clicking here](http://www.google.com/privacy.html).

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We do not share voluntary or non-voluntary information gathered by us by means other than explained above.

## Security

Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. Only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.

## Opt-Out Policy

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:

  * Opting not to receive our electronic newsletters.
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely eliminates the need to collect personally identifiable information from our users.

## Your Consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by us. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this page so that users are always aware of what information we gather, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
